欢迎来到最后一个教程！让我们确保你的磁盘再也不会耗尽。我们将在线扩展一个已满的
repository，把删除释放的空间还给
pool，然后让机器自动完成这两件事。
来看看这个模型。每个 repository
都是共享 datastore
pool 中的一个文件。repository
可以在线扩展，同时 container
继续运行。但在 repo
内部删除数据本身并不会释放任何空间。Trim 才是把数据块还给
pool 的操作。而
policy 则将两者都自动化了。
Fill the repository most of the way
and check:
the filesystem is getting tight.
快满了。是时候扩容了。
Grow it online.
The encrypted container and the filesystem
expand while the containers keep running
— zero downtime,
zero unmount.
现在是四 GB。没有任何重启。
Verify from inside:
same volume,
double the room.
应用程序毫无察觉。
Now the other direction.
Delete the big file — but watch:
the pool does not get the space back
yet.
Deleted blocks stay reserved inside the image.
在 repo 内部已释放，但仍归镜像所有。
Trim hands those blocks back to the datastore
pool,
online.
This is the step most setups forget.
已回收。存储池再次畅通。
Now stop doing this by hand.
The policy enables automatic growth up to
a ceiling you choose,
plus scheduled trims.
策略已保存。接下来由机器接管。
Read it back:
auto-grow on,
ceiling at eight gigabytes,
trim on a schedule.
设置一次，从此无需操心。
And the view that ties it together:
storage health shows every repo's usage,
the pool,
and how much copy-on-write sharing is saving
you.
一个视图：使用情况、节省量和扩展空间。
系列到此结束！十八个教程，从安装到存储自动驾驶。你的服务器又回到你手中了。感谢收看！